<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-18T18:31:10+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/</id><title type="html">SQ Values</title><subtitle>What is SQ? Think you’ve got SQ? Take a closer look.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Secret Ingredient In Sharing Your Faith.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day28-thesecretingredient.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Secret Ingredient In Sharing Your Faith." /><published>2017-04-29T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-29T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/thesecretingredient</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day28-thesecretingredient.html">&lt;p&gt;In the advent of fake news, fake posts, fake social media accounts, fake pictures, fake articles, it’s increasingly difficult to find what’s genuine. Behind the smiles and well-wishes, someone wants to make a sale. Behind the posts, a life is falling apart. People have become so accustomed to seeing what’s false we’ve forgotten what genuine looks like. People can spot a fake a mile away and by the same token, they can also tell when someone is truly being sincere. Sincerity then, is the key to sharing our faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jesus’s time, people of all different upbringings, social classes, economic backgrounds were drawn to Him. There was something magnetic about His personality that made even criminals feel safe around Him. He loved The Scriptures, but He wasn’t religious. He loved people, but He didn’t tolerate sin. He was King, but got down on His knees and served. In every word and act, He loved God and He loved people into the Kingdom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living a life of Faith is simple: &lt;b&gt;Be sincere to God and people.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the eloquence, persuasive arguments or mastery of the scriptures that matters at the end of the day. When it comes to sharing your faith, people don’t care how much you know, they want to know how much you care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Read the story of Zaccheus in Luke 19:1-10. Are you the type of person that people, regardless of their background, feel safe around? Ask God to help you be like Jesus to the people around you.&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">In the advent of fake news, fake posts, fake social media accounts, fake pictures, fake articles, it’s increasingly difficult to find what’s genuine. Behind the smiles and well-wishes, someone wants to make a sale. Behind the posts, a life is falling apart. People have become so accustomed to seeing what’s false we’ve forgotten what genuine looks like. People can spot a fake a mile away and by the same token, they can also tell when someone is truly being sincere. Sincerity then, is the key to sharing our faith.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Good Reason You Don’t Share Your Faith.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day28-onegoodreasonyoudontshare.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Good Reason You Don’t Share Your Faith." /><published>2017-04-29T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-29T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/onegoodreasonyoudontshare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day28-onegoodreasonyoudontshare.html">&lt;p&gt;Disappointment lurks around the corner of even the most mundane experiences: Wearing your favourite shoes and have them rained on. On a date with a special someone who had a change in plans. Checking out that new coffee place across town but it’s closed on the day you go. Someone forgetting your birthday. At the heart of disappointment is our own unmet expectations. But what happens when we are the cause of disappointment; When we are the cause of unmet expectations? Depending on who we’re disappointing it could be nothing at all or it could mean the “End of the World”. Perhaps, disappointment is a reason why Christians have a hard time being 'Christian'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, there’s an unspoken misconception or expectation about Christianity that Christians need to ‘Hallelujah!’ or ‘Praise The Lord!’ in the face of their struggles and not doing so, somehow tarnishes a Christian’s reputation. Perhaps it’s disappointing people, yourself, or even God, is the reason you think twice about sharing your faith. After all if you can’t live up to ‘perfection’, best not to try at all. But Proverbs 24:16 ESV encourages though that &lt;i&gt;“For the righteous falls seven times and rises again.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christianity isn’t about being perfect, it’s about being perfected.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gravest mistake we can make is to give up altogether. To never share who God has become in our lives simply because we’re not “there” yet is like quitting in the first round. We’ll only get “there” if we don’t give up. By believing until we see His Word become real in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will disappoint God, that’s to be expected. But God “will work all things out for our good*”, even our unmet expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:10px;&quot;&gt;*Romans 8:28 ESV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Do you feel like you've disappointed God? Read Matthew 11:28, be real with God tonight and ask yourself if what's stopping you from sharing about Jesus.&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">Disappointment lurks around the corner of even the most mundane experiences: Wearing your favourite shoes and have them rained on. On a date with a special someone who had a change in plans. Checking out that new coffee place across town but it’s closed on the day you go. Someone forgetting your birthday. At the heart of disappointment is our own unmet expectations. But what happens when we are the cause of disappointment; When we are the cause of unmet expectations? Depending on who we’re disappointing it could be nothing at all or it could mean the “End of the World”. Perhaps, disappointment is a reason why Christians have a hard time being 'Christian'.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Speaking For Yourself.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day27-speakingforyourself.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking For Yourself." /><published>2017-04-28T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-28T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/speakingforyourself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day27-speakingforyourself.html">&lt;p&gt;The Rube Goldberg Machine has captivated the imagination of audiences of all ages. People have created increasingly complex procedures to accomplish simple tasks. But the premise of a Rube Goldberg Machine is rather simple: pull a trigger that cascades a series of events that lead to a desired outcome. Once activated, the machine runs it’s course until it reaches it’s end. Our brains are much like Rube Goldberg Machines, and words are a simple trigger that sets off a chain reaction in our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the field of neuroscience begins to expand and help us better understand our brains, a common finding that is emerging from different experiments is that words do have an effect on our minds, and our minds in turn on our overall well-being. People who talk harshly and negatively about themselves, end up displaying harmful behaviour towards themselves. Conversely, people who speak positive words, in turn, exhibit positive behaviour. Words matter because they influence our thoughts, and our thoughts influence our behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If our own encouraging words have a positive effect on our brains, can you imagine what God’s Word can do for us? Is it a coincidence that Paul, centuries ago, reminded the Roman believers not to be &lt;i&gt;‘conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewal of your mind,’&lt;/i&gt; (Romans 12:2 ESV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proclaiming the Bible over does more than release positive self-talk. It adjusts the Rube Goldberg Machines of our minds to trigger a new chain of thoughts and thereby a new outcome: life, as God intended, on earth as it is in heaven. The trigger is simple - open your Bible and speak God’s Word over yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Personalise in your own words the verse of Romans 12:2. Read it out loud, and declare it over yourself.&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">The Rube Goldberg Machine has captivated the imagination of audiences of all ages. People have created increasingly complex procedures to accomplish simple tasks. But the premise of a Rube Goldberg Machine is rather simple: pull a trigger that cascades a series of events that lead to a desired outcome. Once activated, the machine runs it’s course until it reaches it’s end. Our brains are much like Rube Goldberg Machines, and words are a simple trigger that sets off a chain reaction in our minds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Misconception Of Proclaiming And How To Fix It.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day27-misconceptionofproclaiming.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Misconception Of Proclaiming And How To Fix It." /><published>2017-04-27T20:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-27T20:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/misconceptionofproclaiming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day27-misconceptionofproclaiming.html">&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone who has owned a mobile phone can attest to never reading the manual (if there was ever one provided). Smartphones are designed to be so intuitive that we use them almost inherently without much thought. Until a few weeks later, where we see the typical &lt;i&gt;“10 tips to get the most out of your phone”&lt;/i&gt; article that pops onto our newsfeed. Curiously, we click, in order to understand what hidden secret lies beneath the touch screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In like manner, there are words we use without really understanding the meaning of them. We use them out of context, or by association, but when we really think about the meaning, it eludes us. There are some words that when we do learn about their meaning, it gives a much richer context to the sentence we use them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word: &lt;b&gt;‘Proclaim’&lt;/b&gt; comes from the Latin word &lt;b&gt;‘Proclamare’&lt;/b&gt; which means &lt;i&gt;‘to shout forth’&lt;/i&gt; (Pro - forth, Clamare - to shout). There’s an authority inherent to the word that is different from merely ‘saying’ something. When it comes to proclaiming the word of God over our lives, it isn’t merely ‘saying’ or ‘reciting’ verses out loud. It’s speaking it with certainty. Not a repetitious chant or hollow pep-talk, but the genuine belief that His Words have the power to affect the very course of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a joy that comes when we proclaim God’s Word genuinely, not rattling it off like a catchphrase or slogan. There’s a peace of mind that comes when we speak forth His truth over our circumstances instead of mulling on the worst that could happen. And there’s a confidence that comes knowing, if nothing else, God is true to His Word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Has proclaiming the Word of God felt empty and repetitious? Pray and ask God to help make His Words becoming real for you.&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">Almost everyone who has owned a mobile phone can attest to never reading the manual (if there was ever one provided). Smartphones are designed to be so intuitive that we use them almost inherently without much thought. Until a few weeks later, where we see the typical “10 tips to get the most out of your phone” article that pops onto our newsfeed. Curiously, we click, in order to understand what hidden secret lies beneath the touch screen.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Super Mario And The Secret To Life.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day26-supermarioandlife.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Super Mario And The Secret To Life." /><published>2017-04-27T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-27T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/supermarioandlife</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day26-supermarioandlife.html">&lt;p&gt;Growing up in the early 80’s, Super Mario Bros. was easily one of the greatest joys and annoyances for anyone who dared to own a Nintendo. It was notorious for presenting players with a very difficult challenge with very limited tries. Every stage was increasingly more hair-raising than the last and required more skill to get the red-suited plumber to the end of the stage. At some point, to the frustration of millions, you’d get stuck and after exhausting your extra lives, you’re back to Level 1-1. All that hard work and progress for nothing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super Mario Bros. is a metaphor for life: there are obstacles in our way to reach our goal. Sometimes it’s straightforward, but every now and then, there’s that one Goomba that gets in our way, or one falling platform we missed. We’d have to start again. We can find ourselves in the same predicament. There’s always that one struggle, that one recurring sin that messes us up and we have to start again. Sometimes we can’t beat it, and rather not deal with it, we turn off the console and walk away. But walking away doesn’t beat the stage, or clear the challenge. It leaves us unable to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Super Mario, there are greater things beyond the challenges on the stage. Ultimately, it’s to beat Bowser and his minions &lt;i&gt;(our enemy)&lt;/i&gt;, conquer the castle &lt;i&gt;(our challenges)&lt;/i&gt; and save the princess &lt;i&gt;(things that are important to us)&lt;/i&gt;. But none of that happens if we put the controller down. There are greater things beyond the current challenges we face in life, but none of that happens if we give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is not trying harder, but like Mario, it’s getting the &lt;b&gt;‘power-ups’&lt;/b&gt;: the invincibility stars, the 1-UPs, the mushrooms and the Fire Flowers. As a Christian, our ‘power-ups’ are scattered all over the Word of God. It’s matter of digging in and finding them; and the next time life hits us hard, it’s a matter of using them. That’s what proclaiming God’s Word does to our lives. It’s the power-ups we need to turn the trials into triumphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing life without proclaiming God’s Word is like finishing Super Mario without power-ups: it’s harder, more complicated and most of all - NOT the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Do you feel powerless to change? In Acts 1:8 Jesus says we will receive power when the Holy Spirit comes upon us. Read Acts 1:8 and ask God for His Spirit to power you up in that area you need change in.&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">Growing up in the early 80’s, Super Mario Bros. was easily one of the greatest joys and annoyances for anyone who dared to own a Nintendo. It was notorious for presenting players with a very difficult challenge with very limited tries. Every stage was increasingly more hair-raising than the last and required more skill to get the red-suited plumber to the end of the stage. At some point, to the frustration of millions, you’d get stuck and after exhausting your extra lives, you’re back to Level 1-1. All that hard work and progress for nothing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spilling Coffee And Faith.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day26-spillingcoffeeandfaith.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spilling Coffee And Faith." /><published>2017-04-26T20:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-26T20:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/spillingcoffeeandfaith</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day26-spillingcoffeeandfaith.html">&lt;p&gt;Coffee is arguably one of the greatest discoveries of mankind in the last century. Everyone has their preferred way to enjoy coffee. None of which involves spilling it on clothes. At some point in our lives we’ve either seen or experienced the heart-jolting scare of spilling coffee. As soon as you realise it’s happening you’re in a shocked, uncomfortable panic. You do everything to try to clean up the mess, but sometimes you make it worse. Everywhere you go people can see it, and for the rest of the day you’ve got to deal with it; you become more conscious about yourself than you were ten minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sin is a lot like spilling coffee. One minute the slate of our hearts is clean, the next, we’re in panic, returning to our knee-jerk reaction to do our best to cover it up. We try to make the most of it, like the coffee on our shirt, but no matter the smile we force on our face, the shame of it is crippling. Much like sin. We can wear a mask, but eventually the guilt will eat us up. But we don’t have to wear guilt like a coffee stain. The Cross is the reminder that we don’t have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re given this wonderful coffee cup of life, but sometimes (many times) we spill it. The Gospel not only affords us a new cup of coffee, but new clothes to replace the stained ones. The greatest part: it’s not a one time offer. Every time we ask God for help, every time we proclaim God’s word in our lives, we send out an SOS. For God to fix our mess, to take over, to get involved. For Him to begin the cleanup process, no matter how bad and ugly the mess is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Have you felt like you got coffee spilt on your soul? Read Psalms 51:9-11 and speak it over your life today!&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">Coffee is arguably one of the greatest discoveries of mankind in the last century. Everyone has their preferred way to enjoy coffee. None of which involves spilling it on clothes. At some point in our lives we’ve either seen or experienced the heart-jolting scare of spilling coffee. As soon as you realise it’s happening you’re in a shocked, uncomfortable panic. You do everything to try to clean up the mess, but sometimes you make it worse. Everywhere you go people can see it, and for the rest of the day you’ve got to deal with it; you become more conscious about yourself than you were ten minutes ago.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three Ways To Tell If You Have A ‘Religious Attitude’.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day25-threewaystotellifyoustink.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three Ways To Tell If You Have A ‘Religious Attitude’." /><published>2017-04-26T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-26T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/threewaystotellifyoustink</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day25-threewaystotellifyoustink.html">&lt;p&gt;The more we understand God’s word, the more we understand what’s right and wrong. How we practice God’s word can make a difference in being Christlike or being religious. A religious attitude stinks. Like really bad body odour after a hard workout or a humid walk under the sun, everyone notices it except you. Some might be kind enough to point it out, while others just avoid you entirely. Regardless, people can smell a religious, insincere attitude a mile away. But believing in God doesn’t make you stinky, your attitude does. Here’s three ways you can keep your holy ‘underarms’ in check:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Am I comparing Inches to Miles?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Every person is on a different place in their walk with God, some are much further along the way than others. Our job isn’t to penalise people when they don’t meet the same convictions as we do, that’s the Holy Spirit’s role. Our job is to speak the truth in love. To not tolerate sin, but imitate God’s love. After all, we ourselves have our own things we’re wrestling with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Am I comparing Specks to Planks?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s easy, even tempting at times to compare others to our standards and allow their shortcomings to justify our own. For example, ‘I may struggle with porn, but at least I don’t sleep around.’ We are not our own, nor each other’s benchmark. The Bible is, and it’s against God’s word that we should measure ourselves. No more, no less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Am I comparing Lines Crossed to The Cross?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;People will make mistakes and cross our lines, when they do, will we remember The Cross covering our own? It’s easy to point out a fault and leave it at that, but it takes more effort to point out a fault and love the person until they understand we value them over their fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are responsible for our own actions, words and thoughts first and foremost. And the more we have of God’s word in our lives, the more we ought to be careful to see it practiced before it is preached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Do you compare yourself to others? Are you more aware of the lines others cross or the lines you cross?&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">The more we understand God’s word, the more we understand what’s right and wrong. How we practice God’s word can make a difference in being Christlike or being religious. A religious attitude stinks. Like really bad body odour after a hard workout or a humid walk under the sun, everyone notices it except you. Some might be kind enough to point it out, while others just avoid you entirely. Regardless, people can smell a religious, insincere attitude a mile away. But believing in God doesn’t make you stinky, your attitude does. Here’s three ways you can keep your holy ‘underarms’ in check:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are You A ‘Religious’ Person?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day25-areyoureligious.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are You A ‘Religious’ Person?" /><published>2017-04-25T20:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-25T20:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/areyoureligious</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day25-areyoureligious.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Religious.&lt;/b&gt; It’s a label used to describe people with inflexible conditions, imposed on others, and the perception that these people are better than everyone else. It’s not a new label. In fact, everyone has a tendency to be “religious” because “being religious” was less about what you believe and more about how you behave. A vegan can be just as devoted to his/her cause as a street evangelist, and a person lobbying for climate change. So what does it really mean to be religious? Does simply adhering to a belief system make you religious?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus tells a story in Luke 18 ESV where,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Two men went up into the temple to pray, one a Pharisee and the other a tax collector. The Pharisee, standing by himself, prayed thus: ‘God, I thank you that I am not like other men, extortioners, unjust, adulterers, or even like this tax collector. I fast twice a week; I give tithes of all that I get.’ But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’ I tell you, this man went down to his house justified, rather than the other. &lt;b&gt;For everyone who exalts himself will be humbled, but the one who humbles himself will be exalted.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both men believed in God, but there was a stark difference between the two. One acknowledged his achievements for God, the other acknowledged his need of Him. An exalted, religious attitude, is self-focused. While a humble one acknowledges the need for help. Like the pharisee and the tax collector, we can believe the same God, but what comes out of our mouth tells a great deal about what’s really in our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me ask this another way: What’s the difference between a Christian and a non-christian? The Answer: Nothing, except Jesus. Without Jesus, without the cross, we are no different from people who believe or do not believe. That is both a sobering thought and a safeguard as a believer. We are no different, but because of Jesus we can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Read the story in Luke 18 again. Do you find yourself more like the pharisee or the tax collector?&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">Religious. It’s a label used to describe people with inflexible conditions, imposed on others, and the perception that these people are better than everyone else. It’s not a new label. In fact, everyone has a tendency to be “religious” because “being religious” was less about what you believe and more about how you behave. A vegan can be just as devoted to his/her cause as a street evangelist, and a person lobbying for climate change. So what does it really mean to be religious? Does simply adhering to a belief system make you religious?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Words Will Never Hurt Me! (Until They Do).</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day24-wordswillneverhurtme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Words Will Never Hurt Me! (Until They Do)." /><published>2017-04-25T02:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-25T02:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/wordswillneverhurtme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day24-wordswillneverhurtme.html">&lt;h2&gt;“Sticks and stones will break my bones, but words will never hurt me.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a schoolyard rhyme, it made for a quick retort to a bully poking fun at kids. Unfortunately, studies are finding that words DO have an effect on people, both in a positive and negative way.&lt;i&gt;&quot;Death and life are in the power of the tongue, and those who love it will eat its fruits&quot;&lt;/i&gt;, as mentioned in &lt;b&gt;Proverbs 18:21 ESV&lt;/b&gt;. Proclaiming words isn’t merely speaking what’s on your mind, it’s a matter of life and death: either building up or breaking down another person or even ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we proclaim can make a difference. We could be getting all the compliments in the world and all it will take is one bad report to shut us down. In the same way, one genuine encouragement can change the course of a person’s life. We are in the habit of speaking life or death over others and ourselves especially. Oddly enough, it’s easier to believe the worst about ourselves than the best. Words that just make us feel good about ourselves isn’t enough to deal with deep issues in our hearts. We need words that are loving, truthful, and brutally honest at times, and the Bible is that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hebrews 4:12 ESV&lt;/b&gt; describes the Word of God as &lt;i&gt;“living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart.”&lt;/i&gt; It’s wise, comforting and encouraging but doesn’t pull any punches when need be. If a genuine chat with a friend can do wonders for your soul, can you imagine what an honest conversation with God, who really knows you inside out, can do? Let God have a say in who you are, and what’s happening in your life and watch how it can change you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What negative words are bringing you down? Read Isaiah 40:29-31. Speak verse 31 over your life tonight.&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">“Sticks and stones will break my bones, but words will never hurt me.” As a schoolyard rhyme, it made for a quick retort to a bully poking fun at kids. Unfortunately, studies are finding that words DO have an effect on people, both in a positive and negative way.&quot;Death and life are in the power of the tongue, and those who love it will eat its fruits&quot;, as mentioned in Proverbs 18:21 ESV. Proclaiming words isn’t merely speaking what’s on your mind, it’s a matter of life and death: either building up or breaking down another person or even ourselves.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good News Today And Everyday.</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day24-goodnewstoday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good News Today And Everyday." /><published>2017-04-24T20:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-24T20:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/goodnewstoday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/sqvalues/sqv-day24-goodnewstoday.html">&lt;p&gt;The road of life is fraught with pain, pleasures, joys and sorrows. Challenges in life are inevitable, for conflict is at the very nature of change. Going from 'what is' to 'what can be' is uncomfortable and perilous at times. Yet often, it's through change and conflict that we experience the fullest of life that God intended for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is why the Gospel is not for a moment of life, it's &quot;Good News&quot; for every facet of it. Without the Gospel, we are left to navigate life's conflicts by ourselves. If decisions don't work out the way we want, we're left with a downward spiral of failure and self-pity. If they do, we set ourselves upward on the slippery slope of pride and arrogance. Life becomes this tight-rope act where one false step sends us tumbling to our end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gospel is the sweet spot. It's &quot;Good News&quot; because it brings us back to the abundant life God intended for us by allowing Him to once again, become a part of our lives. God IS the strength of our hands and, in our weakness, His grace is made perfect. The Gospel isn't just a Get-Out-Of-Jail FREE card, it's a bridge between two worlds: ours and His. The more we allow the Gospel to influence our lives, the bigger that bridge becomes; the more the reality of His world can become the reality of ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Is there an area of your life that you need some Good News in? Proclaim Deuteronomy 31:6 over your life today!&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Team SQ</name></author><summary type="html">The road of life is fraught with pain, pleasures, joys and sorrows. Challenges in life are inevitable, for conflict is at the very nature of change. Going from 'what is' to 'what can be' is uncomfortable and perilous at times. Yet often, it's through change and conflict that we experience the fullest of life that God intended for us.</summary></entry></feed>